Guide to the postcard album 'Egypt and Palestine' from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref164
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
'Egypt and Palestine' postcard album - Hisham Khatib Collection
1910s-1920s
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.030_ref164
94 Photographic Prints 94 postcards over 50 pages of an album
E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164
Palestine; Jordan; Egypt; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Postcards
- The front cover of the album "Egypt and Palestine" with floral embossing., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  English Writing; Egypt; Palestine
- The inside front cover of the Album "Egypt and Palestine.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Egypt; Palestine
- From the top down: A postcard of the Ras-El-Tin Lighthouse, a hand-colored postcard of the Ramleh Station in Alexandria, and a postcard of Mehemet-Ali Palace and Mansheya Square in Alexandria., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000003; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Lighthouses; Electricity; Trams; Transportation; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Coast; Water; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Men; Shops; Buildings; Alexandria, Egypt; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Women; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Monuments/Memorials; Signs/Signposts; Animals
- Top: A hand-colored postcard of Pompey's Pillar and the Sphinx in Alexandria. Bottom: a postcard of Fairhaven Hotel in Palais Ramleh, Alexandria., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Monuments/Memorials; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Buildings; Hotels; French Writing
- From the top down: a postcard of the Fairhaven Hotel in Palais Ramleh, Alexandria; a postcard showing a general view of the harbor at Port Said; and (No.333) a hand-colored postcard of ships in the Suez Canal., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000005; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); Carl Andelfinger & Co, München; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Buildings; Hotels; Port Said, Egypt; Alexandria, Egypt; French Writing; Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Canals; Deserts; Flags
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of men by tents in the desert; a hand-colored postcard of a man ploughing with cattle; and a postcard of a group of people crossing a bridge with a camel, with a man riding a donkey in the background., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Agriculture/Farms; Landscapes; Tents; Mountains/Hills; Regional/National Dress; Irrigation; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Transportation; Machines; Camels; Group Portraits; Donkeys; Men; Countryside/Rural
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a women on a carriage and a man standing in Egypt. Bottom: [No.66] a hand-colored postcard of a man and a woman with a donkey., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000007; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Regional/National Dress; Niqab/Burqa; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Deserts; Animals; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Donkeys; Palm Trees; Buildings; Head Covers/Veils
- From the top down: a man guiding a camel over a bridge, a hand-colored postcard of people beside the Nile, and a hand-colored postcard of boats on the bank of the Nile., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000008; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Egypt; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Bridges; Palm Trees; Buildings; Camels; Men; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Niqab/Burqa; Boys; Children; Sheep; Animals; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Coast; Trains
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a group of people sitting under a date palm (Equipage Égyptien). Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a family with a camel and donkey., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000009; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Egypt; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Mosques; Architecture; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Camels; Animals; Facial Hair; Religious Sites; Pilgrims; French Writing
- Top: a painted postcard of a street in Egypt. Bottom: a painted postcard of women and a boy in an alleyway., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Paintings; Postcards; Mosques; Streets/Roads; Religious Sites; Crowds; Donkeys; Animals; Egypt; Shops; Street Vendors; Men; Regional/National Dress; Women; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Buildings
- From the top down: A postcard of a group walking near a town on the banks of the Nile, a hand-colored postcard of boys and men with water buffalos in the Nile during a flood, and a hand-colored postcard of a man and a boy working with sugarcane., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000011; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Egypt; Men; Boys; Children; Animals; Group Portraits; Camels; Cattle/Cows; Coast; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Streets/Roads; Street Vendors; Workers; Hats; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; French Writing
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a group of water carriers, Cairo. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a woman seated with two scribes., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Paintings; Postcards; Group Portraits; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Workers; Water; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Shops; Cairo, Egypt
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a man holding a smoking pipe/shisha in regional dress (Fumeur de Hachiche). Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a carriage and two men walking in front of it in Saïs, Egypt., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000013; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Men; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Smoking; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Horses; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Palm Trees; French Writing
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of two people in front of an ornate doorway in Egypt. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of Sheikh el-Anwar's house, Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000014; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Paintings; Postcards; Doors/Entrances; Architecture; Buildings; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Signatures; French Writing; Houses; Girls; Head Covers/Veils
- A hand-colored postcard of a woman from Cairo wearing regional dress., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000015; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; French Writing; Jewelry; Cairo, Egypt
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of a caravan of camels near the Great Pyramids, a view of the City of the Dead and the Mosque of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaytbay, and a hand-colored postcard of the Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan and Al-Rifa'i Mosque., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Mosques; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cairo, Egypt; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Camels; Animals; Deserts
- Top: a postcard of the City of the Dead and the Funerary Complex of Sultan al-Ashraf Barsbay. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Aqsunqur Mosque (Blue Mosque) in Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000017; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Tombs/Mausoleums; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Horses; Animals; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Women; Children; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Cameras; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay; French Writing
- A blank page in the Album "Egypt and Palestine.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
- From the top down: a view of the Shahin Al-Khalwati mosque, and two views of tombs and mausoleums in the Southern Cemetery, City of the Dead, Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Tombs/Mausoleums; Monasteries/Convents; Mountains/Hills; Deserts; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mokattam, Cairo, Egypt
- Three views of the road leading to the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000020; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Giza, Egypt; Trams; Streets/Roads; Transportation; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Men; Women; Boats/Ships; Railways; Bridges; Buildings; Water; Rivers; Landscapes
- Three views of the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Water; Palm Trees; Rivers; Landscapes; Giza, Egypt; Camels; Men; Group Portraits; Animals; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
- Three views of the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Deserts; Architecture; Men; Camels; Animals; Giza, Egypt
- Three views of the Great Sphinx of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Deserts; Landscapes; Architecture; Pyramids; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Camels; Animals; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of the Church of the Epiphany in Port Said, a landscape of Al Qantara, and a hand-colored postcard showing a panoramic view of Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000023; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Forts/Castles; Postcards; Buildings; El-Qantara el-Sharqîya, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Ports; Camels; Men; Animals; Women; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Palm Trees; Cairo, Egypt; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Mountains/Hills; French Writing
- Two views of boats on the Nile river. The top is a postcard showing a dahabeya and the bottom is a painting of a felucca., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000024; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Paintings; Men; Regional/National Dress; Water; Giza, Egypt; Rivers; Pyramids; Architecture; Palm Trees; Nile River; French Writing
- Three hand-colored postcards from the top down: two feluccas on the Nile, (No. 36) the Aswan Dam, and a boat on the Nile., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dams/Barrages; Water; Nile River; Rivers; Aswan, Egypt; French Writing; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Palm Trees; Transportation
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of the obelisk at Heliopolis. Bottom: a painting of an alleyway., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Donkeys; Animals; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; Egypt
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of a caravan, a hand-colored postcard of the harbor and Maison Hollandaise in Port Said, and drawings of ancient Egyptians on leather., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000027; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Streets/Roads; Camels; Animals; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Port Said, Egypt; Ports; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; French Writing
- Top: a painting of the Great Sphinx of Giza. Bottom: a postcard of the entrance to the canal at Port Said., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; English Writing; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Pyramids; Ports; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Flags; Palm Trees; Port Said, Egypt; Giza, Egypt; Buildings
- Top: a view of three feluccas sailing during sunset. Bottom: a postcard of the National Hotel on Suleyman Pasha Street (now Talaat Harb Street), Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000029; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Boats/Ships; Water; Nile River; Rivers; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Hotels; Cairo, Egypt; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Animals; Street Lamps
- Top: (No. 893) a hand-colored postcard of a group of men making a fire. Bottom: (No.776) a hand-colored postcard of women and children in a village., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  French Writing; Italian Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Photographic Prints; Postcards; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Water; Countryside/Rural; Palm Trees; Children; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Egypt
- From the top down: a postcard of the Channel Company offices in Port Said, (No.6) a postcard of the Qasr-El-Nil Bridge in Cairo and a hand-colored postcard of Zahlé and Mount Lebanon., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000031; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Zahle, Beqaa, Lebanon; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Bridges; Palm Trees; Men; Nile River; Cairo, Egypt; Street Lamps; Electricity; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Ports; Port Said, Egypt; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; French Writing; English Writing
- A painting of people selling bread at a market., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000032; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Paintings; Group Portraits; Men; Children; Women; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Food; Street Vendors; Workers; Markets; Egypt
- A painted postcard of people on a hillside in the Upper Kidron Valley., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000033; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Paintings; Postcards; Men; Regional/National Dress; Kidron Valley; Group Portraits
- From the top down: verso of a postcard, a postcard of the Tombs of the Kings in Jerusalem, and a hand-colored postcard of a man carrying water in a village near Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000034; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Countryside/Rural; Jerusalem; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites; Bridges; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; French Writing; German Writing
- A panoramic postcard of the Dome of the Rock and Al-Aqsa Compound., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000034_002; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  German Writing; Postcards; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Jerusalem; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills
- Top: (No.2) a hand-colored postcard showing an interior view of the Pool of Bethesda. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Gate of Judgement (Seventh Station) in the Via Dolorosa., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000035; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; French Writing; German Writing; Men; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Group Portraits
- Top: (No.18) a hand-colored postcard of St. Stephen's Gate (Lions' Gate) in Jerusalem Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Fifth Station of the Via Dolorosa., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000036; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Men; Boys; Children; Facial Hair; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits
- Top: a painted postcard of the front courtyard of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Bottom: (No.3) a hand-colored postcard of the ruins of St. Anne's Church near the Pool of Bethesda., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000037; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Postcards; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; Street Vendors; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Men; Markets; French Writing; German Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a crowd in the courtyard of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a general view of Jerusalem and the Jerusalem Railway Station., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000038; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Crowds; Religious Sites; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Streets/Roads; Jerusalem; Mountains/Hills; Railways; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Animals; Landscapes; Buildings; Street Vendors; Signatures
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of the Church of the Dormition, a hand-colored postcard showing the landscape of Siloam (Silwan), and (No.10) a postcard of oil lamps in a museum near St. Anne's Church, Jerusalem (including a Biblical reference)., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000039; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; French Writing; German Writing; Religious Sites; Churches; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Siloam/Silwan; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Museums; Lanterns/Lamps
- Three hand-colored postcards from the top down: a group of tinsmiths in their shop in Cairo, the Avenue of the Sphinxes in Luxor, and a landscape of Raouché (Pigeons' Rock), Beirut., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000040; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Men; Boys; Workers; Group Portraits; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Street Vendors; Lanterns/Lamps; Cairo, Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; Animals; Water; Seas; Beirut, Lebanon; Luxor, Egypt; French Writing
- Top: a postcard of the Tree of Virgin Mary in Al Matariyyah, Cairo. Bottom: a postcard of a painting of two men in regional dress, caption is verse Micah 7:14., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000041; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Cairo, Egypt; Gardens; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Postcards; Paintings; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Canes/Walking Sticks; German Writing; Facial Hair
- Top: a postcard of a painting of men fishing in the Sea of Galilee, with sailboats in the background; caption is verse Matt 4:18 and John 11:3. Bottom: a postcard of a landscape of Tiberias and the coast of the Sea of Galilee., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000042; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)